[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以，无论在哪里，我们都应该使用构图良好的元素
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So, we should use elements of good composition wherever
适用，我认为我们应该，例如，在逗号后使用空格，
applicable and I think we should, for example, use a space after a comma,
不是在逗号之前。
not before a comma.
这就是我们在文学风格中的做法。
That's how we do it in literary style.
在编程风格中，除非我们有明确的证据，否则我们应该做同样的事情
In a programming style, we should do the same thing unless we have clear evidence
从这种差异中产生的利益。
of a benefit that occurs from that difference.
因为我们已经把所有这些教育都锁定在我们的大脑里了
Because we already have all this education locked into our brains about
这种模式。
those sorts of patterns.
我们可以利用这一点让它变得更容易
We can use that to make it easier for
编写我们的程序。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：现在
writing our programs. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Now
编程比编写需要更高的精确度，所以
programming requires significantly more precision than writing does, so
我们需要更多的规则。
we'll need additional rules.
例如，我建议我们使用空格来消除父母的歧义。
For example I propose that we use spaces to disambiguate parents.
我们使用父代来指示语句的某些部分，以指示调用和
We use parents to indicate parts of statements, to indicate invocations and
函数定义和分组。
function definitions and grouping.
因此，为了帮助我们区分这些情况，我提出了一个规则。
And so to help us to distinguish those cases, I propose a rule.
在函数名和左Paren之间没有空格。
There is no space between a function name and a left paren.
所有其他名字之间总是有一个空格，还有一个左帕伦。
And there's always one space between all other names, and a left paren.
所以，根据这个规则，这些形式都是错误的。
So, by that rule these forms are all wrong.
例如，return不是这种语言中的函数。
For example, return is not a function in this language.
所以，我们不应该让它看起来像一个函数调用。
So, we shouldn't make it look like a function invocation.
现在你可以争辩，有人可以很容易地理解这些是什么意思，对吧？
Now you can argue, well someone could easily figure out what these mean, right?
所以这无关紧要。
So it doesn't matter.
但这很重要，因为你想让阅读的人
But it does matter because you want the person who's reading
你的程序了解程序的作用。
your program to understand what the program does.
你不希望他们在心理上纠正你和校对它，
You don't don't want them to be mentally correcting you and proofreading it,
因为这会分散他们对更重要的工作的注意力
because that is distracting them from the much more important work of figuring out
你的程序做了什么以及我们如何使它更好。
what your program does and how do we make it better.
所以JavaScript的优点之一就是可以立即调用
So one of the good parts in JavaScript is the immediately invocable
函数表达式。
function expression.
今天晚些时候我们将更多地关注这些。
And we'll look a lot at these much more later today.
不幸的是JavaScript的设计没有
And unfortunately the design of JavaScript didn't
预期这是该语言的一个特性。
anticipate that this was a feature of the language.
所以这里我们有一个函数语句，我们想要
So here we've got a function statement and we want to
立即调用该函数，但我们不能，这是语法错误。
invoke that function immediately but we can't, it's a syntax error.
有人认为我们可以将函数包装在括号中。
Someone figured out that we can wrap the function in parens.
该函数现在是一个表达式位置，并且
That function is now an expression position and
现在我们可以立即调用它。
now we can immediately invoke it.
但是你有额外的父母
But then you've got the extra invoking parents
像一对狗球一样挂在一端。
hanging off on the end like a pair of dog balls.
所以我们可以做得更好
So we can do better for
通过将整个调用表达式包装在括号中来实现读取器。
the reader by wrapping the entire invocation expression in parens.
所以现在的目标不仅仅是将其传递给编译器，而是
So now the goal is not to just get it passed to the compiler, but
给读者提供更多的信息，这样当读者看到
to give a little bit more information to the reader, so that when the reader sees
一个函数和括号中的结束括号，这意味着一些东西。
a function and the closing parens wrapped in parentheses, that means something.
这意味着这里重要的不是功能，
That means what's important here is not the function,
这是函数的结果。
it's the result of the function.
只需在一个空间中移动一对，
And just by moving the pair in one space over,
我们给读者提供了更多的信息，这可能是有帮助的。
we give a little bit more information to the reader and that can be helpful.
我们再一次免费做这件事。
And again we do it at no cost.
所以你还记得之前我警告过你不要自动插入分号
So you remember earlier I warned you about automatic semicolon insertion
有时它会把他们放在你认为不应该的地方
how it sometimes puts them in places where you think it shouldn't and
有时不会把它们放在应该放的地方。
sometimes doesn't put them in places where it should.
这就是其中之一。
This is one of those times.
所以这里我们有一个表达式语句，
So here we've got an expression statement,
有人省略了分号，以为系统会添加分号，但是
someone left out the semi-colon expecting that the system was going to add it but
在这种情况下，系统不会添加它。
in this case the system is not going to add it.
因此，我们不是将y赋值给x，而是将调用y的结果赋值为
So instead of assigning y to x, we're going to assign the result of calling y as
函数传递另一个函数的结果作为其参数，
a function passing the result of the other function as its argument,
这不是任何人都会读到的，但编译器就是这样读的。
which is not how anybody would read this, but that's how the compiler reads it.
因此我建议永远不要依赖自动分号插入。
And so I recommend never rely on automatic semicolon insertion.
始终将分号放在正确的位置。
Always put the semicolons in, and in the right place.
如果你不确定它在哪里，你会很高兴告诉你他们去了哪里。
If you're not sure where that is, will be really happy to tell you where they go.
JavaScript有一个with语句，该语句模仿Pascal with语句。
JavaScript has a with statement, which was modeled after the Pascal with statement.
其目的是为了更容易地编写某些类型的函数访问或
Which was intended to make it easier to write certain kinds of function access or
对象访问。
object accesses.
不幸的是，它的设计不正确。
Unfortunately it wasn't designed correctly.
所以这里我们有一个WITH语句和
So here we've got a with statement and
在这里，我们有四个陈述，它展开成。
here we have four statements that it expands into.
有人能猜出这其中哪一个可以吗？
Can anyone guess which of these that will do?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：有人吗？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Anybody?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：可能是第一个。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Maybe it's the first one.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：实际上
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Actually it's
一个骗人的问题。
a trick question.
可能是他们中的任何一个。
It could be any of them.
通过阅读程序，你不可能知道这些程序将会做什么。
There's no way you can tell by reading the program, which of these it's going to do.
实际上，有可能每次执行该语句时，
And in fact, it's possible that every time that statement executes,
可能是不同的。
it could be a different one.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[听不到]O.&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [INAUDIBLE] O. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah,
这取决于O。
it depends on O.
因为它不能知道O是什么，所以没有办法阅读程序。
And since it can't know what O is at time, there's no way to read the program.
所以我们希望有信心我们的程序是完美的，但你怎么知道
So we want to be confident that our programs are perfect, but how can you know
如果你连程序都看不懂，你的程序就是完美的
that your program is perfect if you can't even read the program and
知道它是干什么的吗？
know what it does?
因此，出于这个原因，我建议永远不要使用WITH语句。
So for that reason, I recommend don't ever use the with statement.
你不需要它。
You don't need it.
别管了。
Leave it out.
没有它你会过得更好。
You're better off without it.
现在WITH语句有很多非常聪明的用法。
Now there are a lot of very clever uses for the with statement.
以及发现这些巧妙用途的人
And the people who discover these clever uses
认为他们应该有权使用它，因为它非常有用。
think that they should be entitled to use it, because it's so useful.
但我不是说它没用
But I'm not saying it isn't useful,
我是说，从来没有一个案例不让人困惑。
I'm saying there is never a case where it isn't confusing.
而困惑是敌人。
And confusion is the enemy.
必须避免混淆。
Confusion must be avoided.
混淆是当一个程序看起来做一件事并且
Confusion is when a program appears to do one thing and
它实际上做了其他的事情。
it actually does something else.
另一个词，虫子。
Another word for that, bug.
我们不想要虫子。
We don't want bugs.
所以我想尽可能地消除混乱的根源
So I want to eliminate as many sources of confusion as possible
因为我在努力达到完美。
because I'm trying to attain perfection.
我可能永远也到不了那里，但全能的上帝，那就是我要去的地方，
I may never get there but God Almighty that's where I'm going,
我想尝试制作完美的程序。
I wanna try and make programs that are perfect.
JavaScript有一个双等运算符。
JavaScript has a double equal operator.
我对此有问题，我认为它应该被称为平等。
I have problems with that, I think it should've been called equal.
但这是汤普森对我们做的另一件事。
But that's another thing that Thompson did to us.
但不幸的是，比汤姆森所做的更糟糕的是，它确实是类型强制的。
But unfortunately even worse than what Thomson did, it does type coercion.
因此，首先它看一下它的两种类型的论点，并且
So first it looks at the two types of its arguments, and
如果它们不是相同的类型，它将转换一个或
if they're not the same type it will convert one or
将它们都转换为另一种类型，然后比较该结果。
both of them to another type and then compare that result.
结果，你得到了假阳性，这也意味着你失去了传递性。
And as a result, you get false positives and it also means you lose transitivity.
传递性意味着如果两个事物等于同一事物，
Transitivity means that if two things are equal to the same thing,
那么它们应该是相等的。
then they should be equal to each other.
这里不是这样的。
That's not the case here.
所以当JavaScript被开发出来时，
So when JavaScript was developed,
这被认为是一个好主意。
this was thought to be a good idea.
结果不是。
Turns out it's not.
所以语言的发明者意识到他犯了一个错误。
So the inventor of the language realized he'd made a mistake.
所以当它被标准化时，他去了标准化委员会
So when it went to be standardized, he went to the standardization committee and
说，我搞砸了双倍的平等，但我知道它的修复。
said, I screwed up the double equal but I know the fix for it.
我们只是让它不做类型强制。
We just have it not do type coercion.
我已经在Netscape代码库中测试了它
I've already tested it in the Netscape codebase and
它实际上运行得更快，而且都更小，所以这很好。
it actually runs a little faster and it's all smaller, so that's good.
这是个很大的胜利。
It's a big win.
所以我们开始吧，对吧。
So let's do this, right.
委员会说不，我们要保持现状。
And the committee said no, no, we're gonna keep it the way it is.
但作为折衷方案，我们会给你三倍的优惠。
But we'll offer you triple equal as a compromise.
所以，很多人不喜欢三倍相等，因为
So, a lot of people don't like triple equal because instead of
得走了[噪音]。
having to go [NOISE].
现在你必须去[噪音]并说，是的，三倍相等。
You now have to go [NOISE] and say, yeah triple equal.
始终使用三重相等。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：JSLint。
Always use triple equal. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: There's JSLint.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，JSLint Tell
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, JSLint tell
肯定是你。
you for sure.
JSLint将推荐这种三重相等。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：会修复它吗？
JSLint will recommend this triple equal. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Will fix it?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：它不会修复它，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It won't fix it,
你必须修正你自己的代码。
you have to fix your own code.
[笑]但是JSLint很高兴告诉你可怕的事情
[LAUGH] But JSLint is very happy to tell you about the terrible
你做过的事，但要靠你来弥补。
things you've done but it's on you to make it right.
理应如此。
As it should be.
现在有一些案例。
Now there are some cases.
因为那个双等号意外地做了你想要的。
Because that double equal accidentally does exactly what you want.
那你应该用它吗？
Should you use it then?
我建议不要。
I recommend no.
那就别用了。
Don't even use it then.
因为你不想让读你代码的人问，
Because you don't want the person who's reading your code to have to ask,
他有没有发现Double Equity真正做到了你想要的？
did he find the one case where double equal actually does exactly what you want?
还是他只是无能？
Or is he just incompetent?
[笑]你不希望人们在阅读时问这个问题
[LAUGH] You don't want people asking that question when they're reading
你的密码，对吧？
your code, right?
你想让他们明白它在做什么
You want them to understand what it's doing and
去吧，是的，这是写得很好的东西，我可以让它变得更好。
go, yeah this is well written stuff, I can make this better.
因此，如果语言的某个特性有时会有问题，并且
So if there is a feature of the language that is sometimes problematic, and
如果它可以被另一个更可靠的特征代替，
if it could be replaced by another feature that is more reliable,
然后总是使用更可靠的功能。
then always use the more reliable feature.
这是一个令人惊讶的有争议的声明，但我认为它显然是真实的。
This is a surprisingly controversial statement but I think it's obviously true.
这是在S5中添加的一个特性，多行字符串文字。
So this is a feature that was added in the s5, multiline string literals.
还有许多其他语言以完全相同的方式完成此操作。
There are lots of other languages that do this in exactly the same way.
我觉得这是个错误。
I think it was a mistake.
首先，因为它打破了缩进，因为延续必须是
First because it breaks indentation because the continuation has to be
在边上。
over on the margin.
缩进对于理解我们的组成非常重要
And indentation is really important for understanding the composition of our
程序正确，因为我们有嵌套的函数，嵌套的对象，嵌套的块。
programs right, because we've got nested functions nested objects, nested blocks.
嵌套非常重要，这会破坏缩进。
That nesting is critically important and this breaks indentation.
而且它确实会损害可读性，这是一件坏事。
And it does impair readability and that's a bad thing.
但更糟糕的是，这个语句正确的地方存在语法风险。
But worse than that, there's this syntax hazard where this statement is correct.
这是一个语法错误。
This one is a syntax error.
有人能在第二秒中发现错误吗？
Can anybody spot the error in the second
声明？&gt；&gt；扬声器3：有一个空格在
statement? &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: There's a space at
第二行的开头？&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：没有。
the beginning of the second line? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Nope.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：指向\的空格。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Space Towards the \.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：是的，没错，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, exactly,
这里有个空位。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：你看不到吗？
there's a space right here. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Can't you see it?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah,
一旦你指出它就很明显了，对吧。
it's obvious once you point it out, right.
但我正在努力制作完美的程序。
But I'm trying to make programs that are perfect.
我想看一眼就走，是的，这是完美的，但我不能。
I wanna be a look at and go, yes, that is perfect, and I can't.
所以我不想用这个。
So I don't wanna use this.
我们花了很多时间在大海捞针。
We spend a lot of our time searching for the needle in the haystack.
如果我们的程序看起来不那么像干草堆，我们可以缩短这段时间。
We can cut that time down if our programs look less like haystacks.
因此，避免难以区分的形式
So, avoid forms that are difficult to distinguish from common
错误。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这是另一个
errors. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: This is another one
因为汤普森。
due to Thompson.
他允许您将赋值表达式放入
He allowed you to put assignment expressions in
if语句的条件位置。
condition position of an if statement.
Java做到了这一点，Java说你必须放一些计算结果为布尔值的东西。
Java got this right, Java says you have to put something that evaluates to a boolean.
但后来JavaScript搞错了，回到了C方式
But then JavaScript got it wrong and went back to the C way and
说你可以在里面放任何表情。
said you can put any expression in there.
所以这句话看起来和这句话一样。
So this statement appears to do what this one does.
但它实际上和这个一样。
But it actually does what this one does.
所以你永远不会想写这个。
And so you don't ever wanna write this one.
你想弄清楚你指的是哪一个然后写出来。
You wanna figure out which one you mean and write that instead.
使你的程序看起来像它们所做的那样，而不是让你的读者猜测，
Make your programs look like what they do and don't make your reader guess,
你做的对不对。
did you get it right or not.